Edmund H. Grandahl Papers VHP2005/19
CCSU Veterans History Project
Edmund H. Grandahl Papers
Bulk, 1944
1944, 2005
VHP2005/19
CCSU Veterans History Project
110.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
The collection details Edmund H. Grandahl's experience serving with US. Army Air Corps during World War II. Materials in collection include an oral history interview, service records, book, and photographs.
Grandahl, Edmund H., 1919 -
Biographical/Historical note
Edmund Grandahl enlisted into the U.S. Army Air Corps in 1943; he enlisted into this branch of the service, because he did not wish to be drafted into the infantry. He attended basic training in Greensboro, NC, and then later was transferred to Raleigh, NC for his initial flight training. Grandahl was assigned to a bombardier group, and went to Keesler Field, MI for bombardier training. He was then transferred to Maxwell Field for additional training, but unfortunately washed out of flight school. From there he was transferred to Scott Air Force Base in Illinois, where he was promoted to staff sergeant, and became an instructor for radios and instruments on bombers. He remained there for the duration of the war, and he was able to live off-base with his wife during his service. Upon his discharge, he and his wife took seven months to drive back to Connecticut, using the opportunity to see the country.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Technical metadata of digital objects are extracted and encoded in PREMIS preservation metadata format
Preservation Metadata
United States. Army Air Corps.; United States. Army Air Forces, Base Unit, 3505th.; Flight training--United States--1940-1950; Keesler Air Force Base (Miss.); Maxwell Field (Ala.); Military education; Scott Air Force Base (Ill.); World War, 1939-1945 -- Personal narratives, American
- Series I: Personal Papers, VHP2005/19.I
  - Diploma for Radio Mechanic, AFF course issued by Army Air Forces Training Command, Oct. 10, 1944; VHP2005/19.I.1
  - Discharge certificate, Apr. 11, 1946; VHP2005/19.I.2
  - Discharge Papers, Apr. 11, 1946; VHP2005/19.I.3
  - Separation Documents, 1946; VHP2005/19.I.4; 2.0 Digital objects
  - Letter from Office of Veterans Affairs regarding veterans benefits, n.d.; VHP2005/19.I.5; 2.0 Digital objects
  - Certificate of Appreciation signed by Harry Thuman, n.d.; VHP2005/19.I.6
  - Interview Sysnopsis, Dec. 5, 2005; VHP2005/19.I.7
- Series II: Military Documents, VHP2005/19.II
  - Application for Sugar Ration Book, OPA FORM R-146 (REV.11-45), cira 1940s; VHP2005/19.II.1
- Series III: Publications, VHP2005/19.III
  - 59th College Training Detachment (book), cira 1940s; VHP2005/19.III.1; 86.0 Digital objects
- Series IV: Multi-Media, VHP2005/19.IV
  - Subseries A: Still Images, VHP2005/19.IV
    - Edmund Grandahl in dress uniform, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.1
    - Edmund Grandahl and wife Adaline. Raleigh, NC, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.2
    - Edmund Grandahl and friend Doris Goosman, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.3
    - Squadron H at North Carolina State College. Raleigh, NC, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.4
    - John Griffin, Angelo Gravino, Edmund Grandahl, Jack Kohl at North Carolina State College. Raleigh, NC, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.5
    - Edmund Grandahl on board a Piper Cub aircraft Raleigh Airport. Raleigh, NC, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.6
    - Edmund Grandahl standing by a Piper Cub aircraft Raleigh Airport. Raleigh, NC, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.7
    - Angelo Gravino, W. D. Wiggs, Edmund Grandahl at Raleigh Airport. Raleigh, NC, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.8
    - Jack Kohl, John Griffin, Angelo Gravino, Arthur Dwyer Stooping, Edmund Grandahl at Raleigh Airport Raleigh, NC, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.9
    - Edmund Grandahl and Angelo Gravino in front of a Piper Cub aircraft, Raleigh Airport. Raleigh, NC, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.10
    - Edmund Grandahl by a Piper Cub aircraft, Raleigh Airport. Raleigh, NC, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.11
    - Edmund Grandahl, John Griffin, W.D. Wiggs, Arthur Dwyer, Angelo Gravino at Raleigh Airport. Raleigh, NC, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.12
    - Edmund Grandahl and John Price, a friend from Duke University North Carolina State College. Raleigh, NC, 1944; VHP2005/19.IV.13
  - Subseries B: Moving Images, VHP2005/19.IVb
    - Oral history interview, Dec. 5, 2005; VHP2005/19.IVb.1; 1.0 dvd; Fleeting, Leah (Disk DVD VHP2005/19, Box VHP I #1nterview)